pgatour.com 2008-05-20

# PGATOUR.com - PGATOUR.COM Privacy Policy

Effective Date: January 1, 2007  
Updated: July 16, 2007

Thank you for visiting PGATOUR.com, a general audience site. This privacy policy is applicable to the Website(s) located at the domains "PGATOUR.COM", "GolfWeb.com", and other sites within the PGA TOUR network which may link to this privacy policy (collectively, the "Site") and which are operated by Turner Sports Interactive, Inc. ("TSI") pursuant to a strategic relationship with PGA TOUR LICENSED PROPERIES, INC. ("PGA TOUR") (TSI and PGA TOUR collectively referred to herein as "we", "our", or "us").

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, we provide this statement explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used at PGATOUR.com. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered through and in connection with this web site and do not necessarily reflect our practices for other sites operated by TSI or the practices of third parties other than TSI who operate sites which may be linked to from this web site such as [www.shop.pgatour.com](http://www.shop.pgatour.com/)

### THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

At our site, you may now or in the future be able to order products, enter contests, contribute to charity, vote in polls or otherwise express an opinion, subscribe to one of our services such as our online newsletters, or participate in one of our online forums or communities. The types of personally identifiable information that may be asked to be submitted include: name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, date of birth, gender, credit card information, and information about your interests in and use of various products, programs, and services.

You may also be able to submit information about other people. For example, you might submit a person's name and e-mail address to send an electronic greeting card and, if you order a gift online and want it sent directly to the recipient, you might submit the recipient's name and address. The types of personally identifiable information that may be collected about other people at these pages include: recipient's name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number.

Certain features of our site may only be available to persons who provide us with the requested personally identifiable information such as persons ordering products, programs, and services or otherwise participating in the site's activities and offerings. We also may collect certain non-personally identifiable information when you visit many of our web pages such as the type of browser you are using (e.g., Netscape, Internet Explorer), the type of operating system you are using, (e.g., Microsoft Windows or Mac OS) and the domain name of your Internet service provider (e.g., America Online, Earthlink).

Finally, we may receive and store certain types of information whenever you visit the Site. For example, we may collect Automatic Information and your IP address. As used herein, "Automatic Information" is information collected by our computers when you request Web pages or ads from the Site. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet.

### HOW INFORMATION MAY BE COLLECTED

We may collect information from you in several different areas on the Site, including but not limited to those described below:

### Cookies

As with many Websites, the Site uses standard technology called "cookies," which are small data files that are transferred to your computer when you allow your browser to accept cookies. Cookies automatically identify your Web browser to the Site whenever you visit the Site, and make using the Site easier for you by saving your user ID, preferences and other convenient Site usage information. By tracking how and when you use the Site, cookies help us determine which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the Site are based on data obtained from cookies. Additionally, accepting cookies allows you, among other things, to personalize your experience on the Site. Cookies may also allow the Site to present to you advertising which may be of interest to you as well as limit how often you see certain ads that may detract from your user experience on our Site. If you do not want to allow information to be collected through the use of cookies, you can generally opt out of providing this information by turning the cookies off in your browser. However, some areas of the Site may not provide you with an acceptable user experience if you have disabled the use of cookies.

### IP Addresses and Automatic Information

We may collect IP addresses and/or Automatic Information for purposes of system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers and sponsors. Our computers identify your computer by its IP address. When you request Web pages from the Site, our computers log your IP address. Automatic Information we collect may include, without limitation, such information as the page served, the time, the source of the request, the type of browser making the request, the preceding page view and other such information. When analyzed, this data helps us determine how visitors arrive at the Site, what type of content is most popular, and what type of visitors (in the aggregate) are interested in particular kinds of content and advertising. We may also use Automatic Information to provide you with a more personalized user experience.

### Web Beacons

Consistent with standard practice within the web publishing industry, web pages throughout the Site may contain electronic images (generally, single-pixel ".gif" images) called "web beacons." These web beacons allow us to access certain cookies that were set in a domain different from that which is displayed in the current web page's address bar. Our use of web beacons, includes, without limitation, the following:

  * We may use web beacons within the Site in order to count unique users (actually, unique web browsers), visits and page views. Unique browser recognition is possible through the use of web beacons and associated cookies that may be managed by a third party site analytics partner.
  * We may use web beacons to monitor Site traffic and conversion patterns through our various product and service offerings. For example, web beacons may be integrated into a merchandise product page as well as the subsequent shopping cart, transaction and verification pages. This allows us to determine the most appropriate methods to serve our transaction-oriented customers.
  * We may use web beacons to provide our web-serving applications with access to our cookies. This allows us to personalize your experience when you visit the Site.
  * We include web beacons in HTML-formatted email messages (messages in which we are able to include graphics). These beacons allow us to determine whether or not email messages were opened, links were clicked and notifications/offers were acted upon.

### Registration

In order to take advantage of certain features the Site may choose to offer (including, but not limited to, Site Customization, Newsletters, Contests, Forums, Fantasy Games or other subscription-based services), you may be asked to complete a registration form which will provide us with personally identifiable information. You may also be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to identify yourself during future visits to the Site.

### Newsletters and Site Emails

We may offer newsletters and other email communications to share information with you about sports news and information available on the Site, about certain features the Site may choose to offer or about our affiliates, subsidiaries, business partners, advertisers and sponsors. You may receive newsletters and other email communications by either registering for a particular newsletter or in conjunction with a special feature or membership offering for which you have registered on the Site. You may cancel your email subscription by following the instructions provided on the Site or, in some instances, in the designated area of certain newsletters or emails.

### Contests or Sweepstakes

We may operate contests and sweepstakes through the Site which may require registration. Your personally identifiable information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes. In the event you win a contest or sweepstakes, we may ask your permission to allow us to post publicly some of your information on the Site, such as on a winners page. Except as required by applicable law, we will not post your information without your permission. In some instances, a third party advertiser or sponsor may operate or host a contest or sweepstakes that is promoted on the Site and, as part of the contest or sweepstakes, may collect your information. In those cases (where we are not the operator or host of the contest or sweepstakes), we have no control over the information collected. Thus, before participating, we urge you to review the advertiser's or sponsor's privacy policy as applicable to the contest or sweepstakes.

### Surveys or Voting

From time to time we may request personally identifiable information from you via surveys or voting polls. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information. At times, you may have to register to vote or to take part in a survey.

### Transaction Information

If you purchase a product from us or subscribe to any of the services offered on our Site, we will ask you to complete an order form that will require certain information from you, including credit card number and expiration date, billing address and shipping information, if applicable. We will use this information to complete the transaction that you have requested, i.e., to deliver the products or other services that you ordered, and, if necessary, to invoice you.

### HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION

We may use the information you provide about yourself to fulfill your requests for our products, programs, and services, to fulfill a donation, to respond to your inquiries about our offerings, and to offer you other products, advertisements, programs or services that we believe may be of interest to you.

We sometimes use this information to communicate with you, such as to notify you when you have won one of our contests or when we make changes to our subscriber agreements, to fulfill a request by you for an online newsletter, or to contact you about your account with us.

We use the information that you provide about others to enable us to send them your gifts or cards. From time to time, we also may use this information to offer our products, programs, or services to them. The information we collect in connection with our online forums and communities is used to provide an interactive experience. We use this information to facilitate participation in these online forums and communities and, from time to time, to offer you products, programs, or services.

If you choose to submit content for publication (e.g., questions for an online chat guest, comments sent to our sports personalities, a posting to a or a discussion board), we may publish your screen name and other information you have provided to us (e.g. transcript of the chat, including your question).

We sometimes use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of our site and to enable us to personalize your Internet experience. We also may use this information in the aggregate to analyze site usage, as well as to offer you products, programs, or services. We may disclose personally identifiable information in response to legal process, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. We also may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency's request, or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our terms of use, to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our Web Site and applicable laws or as otherwise required or permitted by law or consistent with legal requirements. In addition, we may transfer personally identifiable information about you if we, or one of our business units, are acquired by, sold to, or merged with another company. Agents and contractors of PGATOUR.com who have access to personally identifiable information are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement by, for example, not using the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for PGATOUR.com. Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that personally identifiable information that is collected will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Statement.

We may also disclose personally identifiable information to companies whose practices are not covered by this privacy statement (e.g., other marketers, magazine publishers, retailers, participatory databases, and non- profit organizations) that want to market products or services to you. If our site shares personally identifiable information, it will provide you with an opportunity to opt out or block such uses. You can opt out from such disclosures, either at the point of submission of your personally identifiable information or prior to any such disclosure. We may on occasion combine information we receive online with other information and outside records to enhance our ability to market to you those products or services that may be of interest to you. If you have signed up to receive our emails and prefer not to continue to receive marketing information from this site, follow the "unsubscribe" instructions provided on any marketing e-mail you receive from this site.

Finally, PGATOUR.com will not use or transfer personally identifiable information provided to us in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you with an opportunity to opt out of these unrelated uses.

### WITH WHOM THE INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED

At times, we may share your personally identifiable information with others for various purposes. The following outlines the ways in which your information may be shared with others:

### Agents

We employ other businesses, certain services and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, sending e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, Site analysis, data analysis, marketing assistance, credit card payment processing, and customer service. These agents may have access to personally identifiable information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.

### Promotional Offers

We may send offers to you on behalf of other partners. When we do this, we do not give that partner your name and address. If you do not want to receive such offers, you may opt out in the email or change your preferences.

### Aggregate Information

We may share aggregate information such as demographics and Site usage statistics to advertisers, sponsors or other organizations. When this type of information is shared, the other parties do not have access to your personally identifiable information.

### Co-Registration Programs

Throughout the Site you may be presented with an opportunity to receive special offers from third parties. Opt-in or opt-out messages will ask you if you would like your information to be shared. If you do choose to have your information shared, your information will be subject to the privacy policy of such third parties. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these other companies and, therefore, you should review the privacy practices of such companies prior to providing your personally identifiable information.

### Third-Party Ad Serving & Audience and Traffic Measurement Services

The Site may use third party network advertisers to serve the advertisements on the Site and may use a traffic measurement service to analyze the traffic on the Site. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to this Site and other Web sites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products and services you might be interested in. Although advertisers and other companies do not have access to your cookies as provided by the Site, the Site's third party network advertisers, the advertisers, the sponsors, and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer if you choose to have cookies enabled in your browser. These third party cookies are set for purposes including but not limited to targeting advertisements to you that you might be interested in, to prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times and to conduct research regarding how useful certain advertisements are to you. Note that any images (or any other parts of a web page) served by third parties in association with third party cookies may serve as web beacons, which enable third parties to carry out the previously described activities. Third party cookies are governed by each third party's specific privacy policy, not this one. Please visit: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp> in order to learn more about the information collection practices and "opt-out" procedures of third party ad servers we may use. Below is a representative list of such third parties and a link to their privacy notices:

  * Atlas DMT: [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or <http://www.atlasdmt.com/privacy/>

### Our Subsidiaries and Affiliates

We may share your information (including, without limitation, personally identifiable information) with our subsidiaries and affiliates.

### Business Transfers

TSI or the PGA TOUR or any of their respective assets, including the Site, may be sold, or other transactions may occur in which your personally identifiable information is one of the key business assets. In such a case, your personally identifiable information, which we have gathered, may be one of the business assets we transfer.

### Charities and Merchant Partners

We work with a third-party credit card processing company, as do many e-commerce web sites. This partner securely manages all customers data in accordance with consumer data protection laws enacted worldwide, including data handling, storage, and security. When you make a donation on the site, you need to provide your name, email address, credit card, and billing information. This information allows us to process and fulfill your donation. You should always consult your tax professional with respect to the treatment of any donation, however, you should be aware that you may not be entitled to a tax deduction with respect to charitable contributions of $250 or more unless you print the appropriate acknowledgement/confirmation page.

### COLLECTION OF INFORMATION BY THIRD-PARTY SITES, ADVERTISERS AND SPONSORS

Our site may contain links to other sites whose information practices may be different than ours. Visitors should consult the other sites' privacy notices as we may not have control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties. PGATOUR.com does not have ultimate control over these third parties' use of this information. PGATOUR.com will notify you at the time of requesting personally identifiable information if these third parties will obtain such information. 

### OUR COMMITMENT TO SECURITY

We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security, and correctly use the information we collect online.

### HOW YOU CAN ACCESS OR CORRECT INFORMATION

Access to personally identifiable information that is collected from our sites may be accessible for a limited period of time from the point of collection. For example, if you create a password-protected account within our site, you can access that account to review the information you provided. You may also send an e-mail or letter to the following e-mail or street address requesting access to or correction of your personally identifiable information. . For verification purposes please include your first name, last name, e-mail address and the password you use for said service.

E-mail Administration   
PGATour.com   
One CNN Center   
Atlanta, Georgia 30303 

### CHAT ROOMS, FORUMS, AND MESSAGE BOARDS

The Site may make chat rooms, forums and message boards available to its users. You are not required to provide any personal information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. If you post personal information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in these areas. Please see the specific terms of use for those areas of the Site.

### HOW TO CONTACT US

If you have any questions or concerns about the online privacy statement for this site or its implementation you may contact us at [privacy.PGATOUR@turner.com](mailto:privacy.PGATOUR@turner.com).

### ACCESS TO PERSONAL INFORMATION

If you created a password-protected account within our site go back to that portion of the site to review the information you provided. You may send an e-mail to request access to or correction of your personally identifiable information. For verification purposes please include your first name, last name, e-mail address and the password you use for said service, if any. If you have any questions or concerns regarding PGATOUR.com's Privacy Statement, you should contact [PGATOUR.com](http://www.pgatour.com/) at [privacy@PGATOUR.com](mailto:privacy.PGATOUR@turner.com)

### UPDATES & EFFECTIVE DATE

From time to time, we may update this privacy statement. We will notify you about material changes in the way we treat personally identifiable information by placing a notice on our site. We encourage you to periodically check back and review this policy so that you always will know what information we collect, how we use it, and to whom we disclose it.

By using this Site, you signify your agreement to the terms of this privacy statement We may update this statement. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the email address associated with your account or by placing a prominent notice on the Site. Your continued use of the Site shall constitute your acceptance of such revised privacy statement.

The Privacy Statement posted on this site was updated on or about July 16, 2007.

Return to Top
